that Musharraf had turned control over
to the United States.
>> We discussed terrorism
in its
entire complexity
within that
hunting every terrorist
was discussed of course
the
the operations against terrorists in
Pakistan on our borders
was discussed.
Prime Minister
Sharif of Pakistan
and also I have to say my favorite field
marshal from Pakistan who's not here but
the Prime Minister is here and you're
going to give his regards. Where are
you?
Peace
has been achieved
after untiring efforts.
Efforts
led by
President Trump
who is genuinely
a man of peace
who has
relentlessly and untiringly
worked throughout these months
day in and day out
to make this world
a place to live with peace and
prosperity.
I would say
that Pakistan
had nominated
President Donald Trump
for
Nobel Peace Prize
for his outstanding extraordinary
contributions
to first stop war between
India and Pakistan
and then achieve ceasefire
along with his
very wonderful team.
And today again
I would like to
nominate this great president
for Nobel Peace Prize
because I genuinely feel
that he is the most
genuine
and most
wonderful candidate for Peace Prize
because
he has brought not only peace in South
Asia
saved millions of people
their lives
and today
here in
Sharm El Sheikh
achieving peace in Gaza
is saving millions of lives in the
Middle East.
Mr. President I would like to salute you
for your
exemplary leadership visionary
leadership
and I think that you are the man this
world needed most at this point in time.
World would always remember you. When I
was when I was stationed in Pakistan in
2002 I was told unofficially that
that the Pentagon controlled the
Pakistani nuclear arsenal.
That Musharraf had turned control over
to the United States because he was
afraid of exactly what you just
described.
But the Pakistanis in the intervening
years and remember I was there 23
years ago
over the last 23 years the Pakistanis
have come to say that is absolutely not
true.
The United States has nothing to do with
the Pakistani nuclear arsenal that
Pakistani generals are the ones that
control it.
So I don't know if if that's true
then I would be very worried about who
is in charge politically in Pakistan.
No. You know for example for example
Imran Khan I can't believe that I forgot
his name. Who's in jail? Who's in jail?
Yes yeah. Right and still wildly
popular. Wildly yeah. He told us when he
was still the Prime Minister he said
listen I've got this political situation
here domestically I'm going to start
blaming you for everything.
And and the ambassador laughed and said
we get blamed for everything anyway so
we don't care.
So everything that happened it was the
United States fault and it was the US
they turned their backs on us and the US
did this and the US did that and then
they arrested him anyway.
So he got a message out to the US
government saying can you help me get
out of this?
And we went to Jemima Goldsmith his gold
whatever name it is
ex-wife.
And she went to Pakistan and asked them
if they would release him and they said
no.
So like you I'm worried about continued
disagreement in Pakistani politics that
has the potential to spill into the
streets because the Pakistanis have a
tendency to get themselves spun up. Mhm.
And people die during demonstrations and
there are attacks against political
figures and assassinations and
and and the country is not known for its
transformative you know leaders making
positive decisions. I'll tell you
another thing.
When Benazir Bhutto was in exile
in Dubai Mhm. I went to see her with
another a senior officer. I went as the
note taker
and
she lived in this
five million dollar palace
on the on the Gulf
and we were sitting in the the front
room the the salon of of the house and
we heard a car pull up.
And she said
her exact words so help me God if he
came home with another Bentley I'm going
to kill him. And I said to my boss
afterwards
she makes $60,000 a year.
She lives in a five million dollar house
and he has a collection of Bentleys.
Aren't they ashamed of themselves? Like
how can they go back to Pakistan and
look the Pakistani people in the face
when their people don't even have shoes
and not food to eat?
Like I understand corruption is a
problem there but that level of
corruption?
Come on. Well those are the kinds of
politicians that the Pakistani people
have to deal with.